COREY CROOKS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER www.coreycrooks.com

CONTACT



412-559-9875



Corey.c.crooks@gmail.com



Cranberry Township, PA



https://github.com/c3rooks



Inkedin.com/crookscorey

EDUCATION

B.S Computer Science

University of Pittsburgh 2009-2014

A.S Applied Science

Community College of AC 2006-2009

SKILLS

Languages:

- Java
- C#
- C
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- Swift

APIs:

- J2SE/J2EE
 - Swing
 - Concurrency
 - IFC
- **ASP.NET Web**
- AngularJS/JQuery

PROFILE

Accomplished software engineer specializing in object-oriented design approaches to network and platform development. Extensive background in full life cycle of software development process including requirements gathering, design, coding, testing, debugging and maintenance. Proven track record of designing and implementing solutions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer UPMC Corporate / 2014 - Present

- Reengineer legacy applications from VB to C#.
- Develop CHIP letters from XML, XLS, HTML and CSS.
- Design and develop new applications for daily automation.
- Develop EOB's to send out to patients on a month to month / week to week basis.
- Develop a data extract (C#) to merge multiple code bases into one specific design and provide regulatory maintenance on the application.
- Develop an ETL process for Oracle to SQL data migration (SSIS/Informatica).
- Develop a parser program to pull data from a text file into a DB.
- Develop workflows for each invoice/EOB.
- Develop a Monitoring tool for Job Tracking.

Database Engineer KIT Solutions / 2013 - 2014

- Developed ETL projects to enhance/produce data migration.
- Developed store procedures for government mental health programs.
- Developed Time-Management application in C# using the entity
- Daily stored procedure bug fixes and updates assigned through Gemini tracking system.

COREY CROOKS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER www.coreycrooks.com

Skills ("continued")

Methodologies:

- Agile
- Waterfall
- SOLID
- UML
- Design Patterns

Databases:

- Oracle
- SQL Server
- JDBC

EXPERTISE

Quality Assurance

Test Driven Development

Troubleshooting

TFS/GIT/Subversion

Software Design

Leadership

INTERESTS

Software Development

Software System tuning and optimization

Solving challenging problems

Learning new technology stacks

WORK EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Software Engineering Internship

Pressley Ridge / 2013 - 2014

- Created, delivered and maintained scalable system architecture to support a high-availability internet site with various internal application.
- Drafted comprehensive reports to document bugs and design flaws.
- Modified legacy applications per government requests.
- Created a mobile MDM solution for classrooms.

Software/Database Engineering Internship

Kit Solutions / 2013

- Developed UML and systems design documents for future Time-Management.
- Daily stored procedure bug fixes and updates assigned through Gemini tracking system.
- Created an ETL application for drug rehabilitation reports.

Patient Business Representative

UPMC Mercy 2009 / 2014

- Reviewed and documented patients medical and insurance information into MEDIPAC system.
- Worked alongside of clinical staff to ensure patients data and information was accurate.
- Implemented HIPPA compliance rules and systems for day to day operations.
- Created solutions for patients to pay for their copay either at the time of service or later.

Patient Transporter

UPMC Passavant 2007

- Transported patients in a timely manner to specific locations within the hospital.
- Assisted clinical staff with medical equipment.